worldbookday.com 2019-04-08

# 

WORLD BOOK DAY PRIVACY POLICY
At World Book Day, we are committed to protecting the privacy and security of our
website visitors. This privacy policy explains the what, how and why of the
information we collect when you visit our website (www.worldbookday.com), enter
any of our competitions/promotions or share your data with us in any way. It also
explains the specific ways we use and disclose that information. By using our
website you acknowledge you have read and understood this privacy policy.
For all our services and for the purposes of EU data privacy law, the data controller is
World Book Day Limited. If you have any questions about this policy or how we use
personal data please contact us:
By email - hi@worldbookday.com
Or post – Data Privacy, World Book Day Limited, 6 Bell Yard, London WC2A 2JR
 This privacy policy explains:
- What personal information we collect and how we use it
- Cookies and other technologies
- Who we share this information with
- How we use your data in marketing materials
- How we protect and store your information and for how long
- Your rights
- Where to direct your questions and concerns about this policy
- What will happen if we make changes to this page
If you are under 13, you must inform a parent or guardian before you use our website
to obtain their agreement to the privacy policy before subscribing to our newsletter or
entering a competition/promotion.
How we use your information
We use your information in a number of different ways. Below you will be able to see
exactly how we use the information we collect:
How we use your contact details and why
We use your responses to competitions and promotions to:
      Help us fulfill competitions – We need to use this information in order to
         contact you if you have won a World Book Day competition/promotion or
         ensure that your prize reaches you safely and securely. If we don’t know who
         you are, we aren’t able to provide you with the prize.
      Send you information via email – We only do this with your permission to help
         keep you up-to-date on World Book Day news, events and competitions.
If you choose not to consent to giving us any of the information above, you may be
unable to enter any World Book Day competitions or promotions.
How we use information we collect about you from your use of our website:
Like many other organisations, we use cookies to collect information about your time
on the World Book Day website (for more detailed information please see the
Cookies section below)
UKMATTERS:48537954.1

We will use this information in our legitimate interests, where we have considered
these are not overridden by your rights, to ensure that:
        Content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and
         for your computer.
        We provide you with the information, products and services that you request
         from us.
        To administer our website and for internal operations, including
         troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey
         purposes.
        To keep our website safe and secure.
        To improve our website to ensure that content is presented in the most
         effective manner for you and for your computer.
        To allow you to participate in interactive features of our website, when you
         choose to do so.
Cookies
Cookies are very small files that are sent to your device, which store information
about your visit to www.worldbookday.com.
We use the following types of cookies:
        Strictly necessary cookies. These are cookies that are required for the
         operation of our website and under our terms with you.
        Analytical/performance cookies. They allow us to recognise and count the
         number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when
         they are using it. This helps us for our legitimate interests of improving the
         way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what
         they are looking for easily.
Disabling cookies
The effect of disabling cookies depends on which cookies you disable but, in general,
the website may not operate properly if all cookies are switched off.
If you want to disable cookies on our site, you need to change your website browser
settings to reject cookies. How you can do this will depend on the browser you use.
Further details on how to disable cookies for the most popular browsers are set out
below:
For Microsoft Internet Explorer:
1. Choose the menu “tools” then “Internet Options”
2. Click on the “privacy” tab
3. Select the setting the appropriate setting
For Google Chrome:
1. Choose Settings> Advanced
2. Under "Privacy and security," click “Content settings”.
3. Click “Cookies”
For Safari:
1. Choose Preferences > Privacy
UKMATTERS:48537954.1

2. Click on “Remove all Website Data”
For Mozilla firefox:
1. Choose the menu “tools” then “Options”
2. Click on the icon “privacy”
3. Find the menu “cookie” and select the relevant options
For Opera 6.0 and further:
1. Choose the menu Files”> “Preferences”
2. Privacy
Where you have not set your permissions, we may also separately prompt you
regarding our use of cookies on the Site.
By using the site you agree to accept cookies. All core parts of the site will function
without cookies, however certain features required this i.e. favourites etc.
Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users and enhance your user
experience. They also help us improve our site. By continuing to browse the site, you
are agreeing to our use of cookies.
Sharing your information
We do not sell any of your personal data to any third party. We do, however, have to
share your data with some other companies, acting on our behalf, in order to ensure
we give you the best possible service:
        Publishers/third party companies who we run competitions and promotions in
         association with/on behalf of, but only if you have won something, in order for
         them to be able to deliver your prize
        Marketing agencies and service providers such as MailChimp, who assist us
         in delivering our marketing strategy.
        Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and
         optimisation of our site and subject to the cookie section of this policy (this will
         not identify you as an individual).
We will disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to
disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or
in order to enforce or apply our competition or promotion terms and other
agreements with you; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of World Book Day
Limited or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and
organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction and to
prevent cybercrime
Marketing
If you have given us permission, we’ll send you marketing by email to keep you up-
to-date with the goings-on at World Book Day.
To stop receiving marketing from World Book Day:
     1 Click the ‘Unsubscribe’ link on the bottom of any marketing email you receive
         from us
     2 Contact hi@worldbookday.com
UKMATTERS:48537954.1

If you do either of the above we will update your preferences so that you do not
receive any further marketing from us.
Storing your information
We will only hold on to your information for as long as is needed to provide you with
our service. If necessary, we will hold onto your information after a competition or
promotion has ended in order to meet legal or regulatory requirements, and to
enforce our terms and conditions.
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers.
Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely
secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot
guarantee the security of your data transmitted via our website or other digital means
(such as email) any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your
information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent
unauthorised access.
Our website may, from time to time, contain links to external sites. We are not
responsible for the privacy policies or the content of such sites.
Public forums
The website may, from time to time, make chat rooms, message boards, news
groups and/or other public forums available to its users. Any information that is
disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise
caution when using these and avoid posting any personal information.
Your rights
You have the right under certain circumstances:
     •         to be provided with a copy of your personal data held by us;
     •         to request the rectification or erasure of your personal data held by us;
     •         to request that we restrict the processing of your personal data (while we
               verify or investigate your concerns with this information, for example);
     •         to object to the further processing of your personal data, including the
               right to object to marketing;
     •         to request that your provided personal data be moved to a third party.
Your right to withdraw consent:
Where the processing of your personal information by us is based on consent (e.g.
for marketing communications), you have the right to withdraw that consent without
detriment at any time by contacting us (hi@worldbookday.com) or clicking the
unsubscribe option at the bottom of any promotional email.
If your request or concern is not satisfactorily resolved by us, you may approach your
local data protection authority, (see http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-
protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.html ).
The Information Commissioner is the supervisory authority in the UK and can provide
further information about your rights and our obligations in relation to your personal
data, as well as deal with any complaints that you have about the processing of your
personal data.
UKMATTERS:48537954.1

Questions or concerns
If you have any questions or comments, or if you want to update, delete or change
any Personal Information we hold, or you have a concern about the way in which we
may have handled any privacy matter, please contact us at hi@worldbookday.com.
Changes to our policy
We may make changes to this page occasionally, reflecting how we use and process
your data. If we make any significant changes to our privacy policy, we will ensure
that you are kept up-to-date via our website, social media or other services, such as
email, so that you are able to review the changes before continuing to use the World
Book Day website.
UKMATTERS:48537954.1
